# callum jones

I want to work for companies that build great products and delivery quality experiences to people. I'm not interested in applications that feel like a burden to use or force them into some sort of cycle, I want to build things that matter to people and people get a genuine enjoyment out of investing their time in. At the same time I want to build applications that help people achieve what they want in life and get out of the way.

I'm not interested in being a pure backend engineer, my most enjoyable jobs have come when while implementing backend functionality I've worked with designers and frontend developers to produce a good end to end user experience. The backend is responsible for holding up the promise of a good experience: if it's slow, requires too many options or doesn't provide a feedback loop the application breaks down as an experience.

I'm interested in working with MVC frameworks on the \*nix environment. I am a big beliver in the skinny controller pattern, moving common actions out of the controller into a 'manager' which simplifies testing and usage in API endpoints. I prefer to implement the view model pattern (+ serializers) when needed to free up the logic from database models.

I believe in the web, whether it be as a delivery mechanism for native mobile applications or as applications themselves. With the backend MVC frameworks shomewhat decided, the attention right now is on how frontend applications should be implemented, I'm a big fan of clientside MVC frameworks consuming the application like an ordinairy API.

I'm always interested in exciting oppurtinities, locally and internationally. If you would like the chat, hit me at <a href="contact@callumi.com">contact@callumi.com</a>

## **Skills**

**Ruby** Developed API and full featured applications with Ruby on Rails. Worked with Sidekiq for background processing.

**JavaScript** Developed frontend applications in Knockout.JS, EmberJS and Backbone.js. Integrated Rickshaw.js (+ D3.js) with MVC applications for simple metric renderings.

**ASP .NET** Worked with ASP.NET MVC 5 (.NET 4.5) with Quartz scheduling, Rebus worker infrastructure, Ninject, Automapper and NUnit.

**Objective-C** Developed iPad and iPhone applications for standalone and client-server setup. Worked with Core Data and FCModel for data persistence.

**Ansible** Built simple Ansible workflows for provisioning of application servers.

Docker Setup Docker environments for simple application reuse, integrated with

Ansible for quick container provisioning.

**Amazon Web Services** Worked with EC2, Route 53 and VPC for complete application environments. Migrated domains to Route 53 and depliyed website/assets to CloudFront on S3.

**MySQL** Worked with optimising queries for reduced disk space and reduced execution times. AWS RDS and local.

**Developer Tools** Git, Visual Studio, Sublime Text

# **History**

#### **Present: Extended**

Building personal iOS application for playback of DJ sets from SoundCloud.

iCloud support for persisting current playback position. Integration with native audio APIs via AVPlayer API.

Developed efficient process for delivering human curated playlists without need for server (via S3), reducing scale bottlenecks.

Released to App Store with continous support and ~400 downloads.

Developed SlimMigration, a open source project for easily migrating basic SQLite databases.

#### Present: Datacom (Western Australia)

Streamlining deployment process of existing Rails application with Docker and Ansible (to support multiple client site distribution).

Providing support as senior Rails developer in team.

#### Present: Local startup (Western Australia)

Managing and developing client's prototype ASP.NET MVC 5 application involving external API aggregation, fast metric aggregation and generation and dashboard.

Architected complete application layout: frontend and backend separation, continuous integration and deployment.

Developed worker system ontop of Rebus API for fast metric generation.

#### 2012 - 2013: Discovr (Western Australia)

Part of team developing backend API for iOS application. Worked with Rails 3.2, MySQL (AWS RDS), Sidekiq, content discovery and extraction, external catalogue integration.

Developed TrackDiscovery, a pipeline for discovering new tracks and delivering content to new users.

Worked with tracking, analysing and optimising MySQL queries while maintaing AWS

una serah.

Developed backend for a frontend application, working with a designer to deliver story pages capable of playing SoundCloud and YouTube content.

#### 2011 - 2013: Corporate Governance Risk (Western Australia)

Part of team developing product for managing and tracking organisation's risks. Worked with Rails 3.2, MongoDB (+ Mongoid), Nginx, EmberJS.

Developed AWS infrastructure for international clients, with application and database redundancy.

Interviewed candidates and managed remote team (India) for delivery of additional application features.

# 2011: CSG (now NEC Australia) (Western Australia) (part-time during study)

Worked with team in developing first iPad application for St John's Ambulance.

Developed features for fast data entry and input of body related events.

Provided support on small ASP.NET MVC 2 application.

#### 2010: Rummble (London) (part-time during study)

First experience working in a startup.

Supported development of Struts 2 application (Java)

Developed Rails + MongoDB based Facebook app for sourcing recommendations from Facebook friends. (Part of Facebook Hackathon)

Upgraded Java backend and iOS application to Facebook Graph API, successfully transitioning users with auto migration flow.

Gained appreciation for clear and concise application functionality.

### **Education**

#### 2008 - Nov. 2011: University of Western Australia

Completed Bachelors of Computer Science majoring in Web and Systems.

Studied Data Structures, Computer Networks, C and J development.

Participated in team project successfully delivering external client's requirements.

#### Early 2010 - Mid 2010: University of East London

Studied Information Security, Network Security and Programming Paradigms.

#### Mid 2010 - Late 2010: Queen Mary, University of London

Studied Computer Image Processing, Multimedia, Distributed Networks and

~	٠.
รคดม	rity.
<i>-</i>	

Developed basic application for "spot the difference" in two images.